Capital District Committee for Palestinian Rights; Records apap163
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Capital District Committee for Palestinian Rights Records
1989-1993
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap163
.2 cubic ft.
This collection includes newsletters, campaign notes, meeting registries and speeches created and collected by the the Capital District Committee for Palestinian Rights.
Historical Note
Based in Albany, New York, the Capital District Committee for Palestinian Rights (CPR) began as an informal coalition of Palestinians, Palestinian-Americans, and supporters in 1982. The organization was a committee of the Albany Social Justice Center and met monthly for several years, and organized an annual dinner.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes newsletters, campaign notes, meeting registries and speeches created and collected by the the Capital District Committee for Palestinian Rights.
The majority of the collection are newsletters from national and international Palestinian support organizations, representing both the human rights perspective and Marxist-revolutionary perspective. The collection also includes photocopies of newspaper articles, campaign notes, meeting registries, and other typescript pages.
The collection provides a timely snapshot of the issues for international Palestinian support organizations after the fall of the Soviet Union. There is only one copy of the organization's own newsletter from 1991.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized alphabetically. There are no series.
Acquisition Information
Donated by the Social Justice Center along with the ACT UP Albany Chapter Records in 2000 October.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Social Activists and Public Advocates; Palestinian Arabs--Social conditions; Newsletters
- Al-Fajr, 1992 (Flat-file 1)
- Breaking the Siege, 1989-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Capital District Committee for Palestinian Rights Newsletter, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- The Link, 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Mailings, 1991; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Meeting Registry, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Middle East Labor Bulletin, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Middle East Report, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- North Star News, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Palestine Affairs, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Palestine Focus, 1991-1992 (Flat-file 2)
- Palestine Focus, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Palestine Human Rights Campaign, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Press Clippings, 1991-1993; Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Settlement Watch, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Soldiers for Peace, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 15)